Earlier on, we talked about the idea of an assignment statement,
刚才我们讲了一个赋值语句的想法
like for example any equals turtle.Turtle.
比如像龟龟
It takes whatever's on the right hand side of
无论在哪一边
the equals sign and it assigns it to the variable that's named on the left.
等号 并将其分配给左边指定的变量
In this case, the code on the right creates
在这种情况下 正确创建的代码
a new turtle object and this turtle object gets assigned to the variable named amy.
一个新的海龟对象 这个海龟对象被分配给叫做 amy的变量
But we don't have to limit ourselves to Turtle objects,
但我们不必局限于 Turtle 对象
we can assign other things to variables too.
我们也可以把其他东西分配给变量
For example, this statement assigns
例如 此语句指定
the string yellow to a variable called a pretty color.
字符串黄色到一个被称为相当颜色的变量
Let's see how we might use something like this.
让我们看看我们如何使用类似的东西
Here's our familiar code that has the turtle "Draw a yellow square."
这是我们熟悉的代码 有乌龟 "画黄色正方形 "
Only we'll change it a little by adding this assignment statement right here.
只有我们在这里添加这个赋值语句来改变它
Now that we've assigned the string yellow to this pretty color variable,
现在我们已经把黄色的颜色分配给了这个美丽的颜色
we can use that variable any place in the code where we need that string.
我们可以用这个变量在代码中的任何地方
So, instead of putting yellow here on this line,
所以不要把黄色放在这条线上
we can put pretty color instead.
我们可以用漂亮的颜色
That will have exactly the same effect.
这将产生完全相同的效果
The turtle will draw a yellow square.
乌龟会画一个黄色的正方形
One of the nice things but doing it this way is
其中一件好事就是这样做
that we can use that variable in multiple places.
我们可以在多个地方使用这个变量
Like if we also had some other turtles drawing some other shapes,
就像我们也有其他海龟在绘制其他形状
we could use the same pretty color
我们可以用同样的颜色
variable to set the color that they're drawing as well.
变量来设置它们所绘制的颜色
Then if we decided that we didn't think yellow was such a pretty color after all,
然后如果我们决定我们认为黄色毕竟不是很漂亮的颜色
we could change the string that's assigned to the variable.
我们可以更改分配给变量的字符串
Like, let's say that now instead of assigning the string yellow,
就说现在不说给串黄了
we'll assign the string, light blue.
我们会把琴弦亮蓝色
So now this name pretty color will refer to the string light blue instead.
所以现在这个名字漂亮的颜色会指的是弦的浅蓝色
The nice thing is that we only have to modify this variable in this one spot,
好的是我们只需要在这个地方修改这个变量
but this string will be getting used in all of these different places.
但这条线将会被用于所有这些不同的地方
So all of these turtles are now drawing in light blue.
所以这些海龟都是用浅蓝色绘制的